[
  {
    "front": "get along (I dont really get along with my sister's husband)",
    "back": "se dar bem",
    "id": 253998938,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "stand out (he stands out)",
    "back": "destacar",
    "id": 283914949,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "roll back",
    "back": "reverter",
    "id": 782883060,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pass along (I will pass this along)",
    "back": "repassar",
    "id": 390686221,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "sum up (summing up)",
    "back": "resumir",
    "id": 831149281,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "take off (it will take off)",
    "back": "decolar",
    "id": 366814313,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "chill out",
    "back": "relaxar",
    "id": 529258483,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "embarrassment (I turned red with embarrassment)",
    "back": "constrangimento",
    "id": 867519524,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "call off (Jim called his wedding off)",
    "back": "cancelar",
    "id": 589390056,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "screw up (I have screwed up so many things)",
    "back": "estragar",
    "id": 657703331,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pull off (I will pull it off)",
    "back": "fazer bem feito",
    "id": 809774856,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "fool around (stop fooling around and get back to work)",
    "back": "enrolar",
    "id": 193540590,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "chew out (the coach chewed his team out for playing so badly / I got chewed out by my doctor..)",
    "back": "dar/levar uma bronca",
    "id": 125468783,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "freak out (I just freak out)",
    "back": "surtar, pirar",
    "id": 228739884,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "hold on (a minute please)",
    "back": "esperar",
    "id": 392244571,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "comprehensive (guide)",
    "back": "abrangente",
    "id": 711121680,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "struggle (I am struggling)",
    "back": "lutar / luta",
    "id": 195867835,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "streamline (it streamlines the development process)",
    "back": "simplificar",
    "id": 775241600,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "to offset (the gains offset the losses)",
    "back": "compensar",
    "id": 241413786,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "backfire (the implementation backfired)",
    "back": "sair pela culatra, produzir efeitos negativos",
    "id": 811377963,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "disclose (terms of the deal were not disclosed)",
    "back": "divulgar",
    "id": 562275754,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "I am stuffed",
    "back": "estou cheio",
    "id": 492164884,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pull over (pull over the car / my brother got pulled over by the police)",
    "back": "estacionar, parar (pare o carro / meu irmão foi parado pela polícia)",
    "id": 378568645,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "gain on (they are gaining on us / Sanders is gaining on Clinton)",
    "back": "alcançar (eles estão nos alcançando / Sanders está alcançando Clinton)",
    "id": 258083006,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "smuggle (if you are smuggling drugs..) / smuggler (he is a smuggler)",
    "back": "contrabandear / contrabandista",
    "id": 326271815,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "breakthrough (scientists are hoping for a breakthrough in the search for a cure for cancer)",
    "back": "avanço",
    "id": 248368514,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "sorrow (he understood the sorrow and discontent underlying his brother's sigh)",
    "back": "tristeza",
    "id": 300616667,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "go after (we will go after ISIS..)",
    "back": "perseguir, seguir",
    "id": 329711996,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "outage (providing phone service during a power outage is another technical problem)",
    "back": "interrupção (serviço indisponível)",
    "id": 441616526,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bribe (the politician was accused of accepting bribes.)",
    "back": "subornar / propina, suborno",
    "id": 854446271,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "on behalf of (I am calling on behalf of doctor Foo)",
    "back": "em nome de",
    "id": 485535802,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "fairness (fairness includes equal application of the law)",
    "back": "justiça, equidade",
    "id": 593782199,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "there may be (a lot of kind computers)",
    "back": "pode haver",
    "id": 274757147,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "shout–out (I would like to give a shout–out to Exame magazine / sempre usa 'to' depois)",
    "back": "agradecer, mandar um abraço",
    "id": 391605494,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "to rush (they rushed the field and got everything",
    "back": "correr, se apressar (eles invadiram o campo e pegaram tudo)",
    "id": 303457972,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "kick the tires",
    "back": "inspecionar algo para garantir que coincide os padrões esperados",
    "id": 202243205,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "get cover (looking for a car loan? We've got you covered)",
    "back": "'taking care of your needs'",
    "id": 337789155,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "home appliance (they sell home appliances)",
    "back": "eletrodomésticos",
    "id": 323537812,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "leverage (the organization needs to leverage its keys resources)",
    "back": "use (something) to maximum advantage / influência",
    "id": 614074237,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "by accident (mom, I broke your vase by accident)",
    "back": "sem querer",
    "id": 361147856,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "come across (I came across your site while searching the internet)",
    "back": "deparar, encontrar (por acaso)",
    "id": 861466572,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "drift off (I drifted off while watching TV / I was so tired that I drifted off)",
    "back": "to fall asleep gradually",
    "id": 542839320,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "apologize for (I apologize for not recording more mini podcasts last week / I apologized to the teacher for being late)",
    "back": "pedir desculpa",
    "id": 467373324,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "for the time being (so, no Postgres for the time being)",
    "back": "por ora, por enquanto",
    "id": 313223148,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "touch yourself / j@ck off / j&rk off",
    "back": "se masturbar",
    "id": 215458744,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "undermine (the president has accused two cabinet member of working to undermine his position)",
    "back": "minar, enfraquecer",
    "id": 646805288,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "elderly (please give up your seat to an elderly or disabled person if they require it)",
    "back": "velhos, idosos (forma educada), old people considered as a group",
    "id": 353212593,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "lead (lead poisoning)",
    "back": "guiar, conduzir / chumbo (envenenamento por chumbo)",
    "id": 361717582,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "job openings (I am curious about job openings)",
    "back": "vagas de emprego",
    "id": 635575270,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "blizzard (we once got stuck in a blizzard for six hours)",
    "back": "nevasca (uma tempestade de neve severa com fortes ventos)",
    "id": 417096834,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bite the dust (he was too young to bite the dust / his carrer bit the dust when he lost his job)",
    "back": "morrer, falhar, fracassar (ele era muito novo para morrer / a carreira dele fracassou quando ele perdeu o emprego)",
    "id": 699316962,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "run out (the paper ran out / I ran out to meet him)",
    "back": "acabar, sair correndo (o papel acabou / eu sai correndo para encontrar ele)",
    "id": 520352503,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "get away (we walked to the next beach to get away from the crowds / we got away for a few days, but now we are back.)",
    "back": "fugir / sair para descansar",
    "id": 586605256,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "look into (the police looked into the disturbance)",
    "back": "examinar, investigar",
    "id": 860992240,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "call the shots (who calls the shots around here? / I call the shots)",
    "back": "dar as cartas, mandar (quem manda aqui? / eu mando aqui)",
    "id": 652749823,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "catch up (the runner caught up to the leader on the last lap of the race / I need a quiet time so I can catch up on my work)",
    "back": "alcançar, ficar em dia, se atualizar",
    "id": 532388222,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "either way (give me a call either way and let me know if you want to come with us)",
    "back": "de qualquer modo (de qualquer modo, me ligue e me avise se você quer ir conosco)",
    "id": 666516660,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "put out (please put that cigarette out / It would be lovely to stay with you, but I dont want to put you out)",
    "back": "apagar fogo (por favor apague esse cigarro), causar problema/inconveniência (seria adorável ficar com você, mas não quero lhe causar problemas)",
    "id": 707245074,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "nasty (plastic bags burn with a nasty smell)",
    "back": "desagradável",
    "id": 807349880,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "terrific (this has been a terrific experience)",
    "back": "excepcional, fantástico, esplêndido (falso cognato)",
    "id": 377771604,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "horny (when you are horny)",
    "back": "excitado, com tesão",
    "id": 290892321,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "yell (you need to yell)",
    "back": "gritar",
    "id": 346632923,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "whatever you do (dont press that button)",
    "back": "faça o que fizer (não aperte aquele botão)",
    "id": 761393032,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "mouther (the mouther Donald Trump)",
    "back": "fanfarrão",
    "id": 813510092,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "silly (what a silly joke)",
    "back": "bobo (que brincadeira boba)",
    "id": 200499880,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "sewer (system)",
    "back": "esgoto",
    "id": 487512781,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "reckless (he was found guilty of reckless driving), recklessness (the accident was a result of recklessness)",
    "back": "imprudente (adj.) / imprudência (noun)",
    "id": 801618551,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "withstand (a bridge designed to withstand earthquakes)",
    "back": "resistir, suportar",
    "id": 700083147,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "draw (the children drew pictures of their families / He is an excellent speaker who always draws a crowd. / I haven’t drawn any conclusions about the murder of the journalist Jamal Khashoggi yet)",
    "back": "desenhar / atrair / tirar (conclusoes)",
    "id": 511275472,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bankrupt (Manchete is bankrupt)",
    "back": "falido (adj.)",
    "id": 389321428,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "go by (we need to go by my tower / could you go by the grocery store and pick up some vegetables?)",
    "back": "passar (por algum lugar)",
    "id": 338330801,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "foster (the teacher's task is to foster learning / competition fosters progress and innovation)",
    "back": "incentivar, promover",
    "id": 194401151,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "whereas (what really happens is that..)",
    "back": "enquanto que",
    "id": 498216727,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "unfold (something is unfolding, being revealed to me)",
    "back": "acontecer (algum coisa está acontecendo..), desdobrar",
    "id": 718632279,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "debut (the game is nearing its public debut)",
    "back": "estréia",
    "id": 240203214,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "go over (thanks, we will go over it)",
    "back": "rever, checar",
    "id": 120236990,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "shortage (shortage of water is growing worldwide)",
    "back": "escassez, falta",
    "id": 322274557,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "shy away (I've never shied away from hard work)",
    "back": "evitar",
    "id": 661329886,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "yield (calling the same function with the same arguments will always yield the same results)",
    "back": "produzir",
    "id": 236139821,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bear (so bear with me / I can't bear the traffic in São Paulo)",
    "back": "fica comigo / aguentar (eu não consigo aguentar o tráfego em SP)",
    "id": 648892835,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "skinny (controllers, fat models)",
    "back": "magro (adj.)",
    "id": 709964118,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "tread (dont tread on me / I trod on a piece of broken glass)",
    "back": "pisar (não pise em mim / eu pisei...)",
    "id": 853264793,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "hazard (the hazards of smoking)",
    "back": "perigo, arriscar",
    "id": 384454855,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "grumble (stop grumbling among yourselves)",
    "back": "queixar, resmungar",
    "id": 754228608,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "whine (stop whining)",
    "back": "choramingar",
    "id": 711805722,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "mean it (when I say I love you, I mean it)",
    "back": "estar falando sério (quando digo que te amo, estou falando sério)",
    "id": 893325334,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "thereafter (we still need couple hours to finish, thereafter SCPC will be available)",
    "back": "depois disso",
    "id": 461909695,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "summon (Elon compares building AI to summoning demons)",
    "back": "convocar, chamar",
    "id": 374716393,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "rig (the results of the elections have been rigged)",
    "back": "fraudar, manipular",
    "id": 176948303,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "in charge (who is in charge?)",
    "back": "quem está no comando?",
    "id": 476844165,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "allowance (there is private healthcare allowance / the recommended daily allowance of vitamin C)",
    "back": "auxilio / dose",
    "id": 887915053,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "capital punishment",
    "back": "pena de morte",
    "id": 517509063,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "yearn (what do you yearn for?)",
    "back": "anseiar (pelo o que você anseia?)",
    "id": 237298419,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "recall (I dont recall what he said / can you recall what he said?)",
    "back": "lembrar (eu não lembro o que ele disse/ você se lembra o que ele disse?)",
    "id": 700804424,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "in a row (they've won six games in a row)",
    "back": "consecutivas",
    "id": 704402149,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "stand for (what does the green stand for?)",
    "back": "representa, significa",
    "id": 783518207,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bridegroom (the friend of the bridegroom)",
    "back": "noivo",
    "id": 159776462,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "easy–peasy",
    "back": "mole–mole (very easy)",
    "id": 723621966,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "annoying (that was annoying)",
    "back": "irritante",
    "id": 540209205,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "cheat on (dont cheat on your wife, dont cheat on at all)",
    "back": "trair (não traia sua esposa, não traia absolutamente)",
    "id": 477387135,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "daunting (it can be daunting)",
    "back": "assustador (isso pode ser assustador) / assustar",
    "id": 648770706,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bigotry (It's time to unlearn our bigotry) (lê–se 'bígôtri')",
    "back": "intolerância (noun)",
    "id": 279246451,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "cheer for (who are you cheering for? / I'm cheering for Palmeiras)",
    "back": "torcer (pra quem você torce? / Estou torcendo pro Palmeiras)",
    "id": 795727369,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "under the weather (I'm a bit under the weather today)",
    "back": "doente, não tão bem (eu estou um pouco doente hoje)",
    "id": 487714882,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "heartbreak (the kidnapping has caused the family months of heartbreak and suffering)",
    "back": "desgosto, grande tristeza",
    "id": 390456279,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "kidnap (the kidnapping has caused the family months of heartbreak and suffering)",
    "back": "sequestrar / sequestro (kidnapping)",
    "id": 402700174,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "shape up (you better shape up / come on, Charlie, shape up)",
    "back": "tomar jeito, entrar em forma",
    "id": 861543258,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "tight (hold on tight)",
    "back": "firme, justo, apertado",
    "id": 319769588,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bleed (do you bleed?)",
    "back": "sangrar",
    "id": 773519357,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "downward (detail should increase as we move downward)",
    "back": "para baixo (up/left/right + ward:  para cima/esquerda/direita)",
    "id": 556889493,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "lean on (we lean on each other)",
    "back": "se apoiar (nos apoiamos uns ao outros)",
    "id": 518971460,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "guts (he has the guts to change)",
    "back": "coragem (ele tem coragem pra mudar) / entranhas",
    "id": 458470907,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "deceased (five of the deceased were employed by the club)",
    "back": "falecido",
    "id": 337176081,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pass away (he passed away)",
    "back": "falecer",
    "id": 643265918,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "lay out (Steve tried to lay out what is going on with the company / 2,500 life jackets were laid out in London to send a powerful message about refugees)",
    "back": "explicar / dispor, arranjar (2500 coletes salva–vidas foram dispostos/colocados em Londres...)",
    "id": 889262889,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "strike, struck (You struck him / Chelsea announces hunger strike..)",
    "back": "atacar (você atacou ele) / greve (Chelsea anuncia greve de fome)",
    "id": 510172137,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "fuel (fuel the car)",
    "back": "abastecer / combustível",
    "id": 361804192,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "helpless / helplessness (a helpless two–day–old baby)",
    "back": "desamparado (adj.) / desamparo (noun)",
    "id": 159075068,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "reach out (I am going to reach out to Bill today)",
    "back": "falar, contactar",
    "id": 335796291,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "disposal (battery disposal)",
    "back": "descarte (descarte de bateria)",
    "id": 246055748,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "flaw (fun but with flaws)",
    "back": "falha (noun)",
    "id": 822914320,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "detour (we had to detour around downtown, so it took us longer than usual)",
    "back": "desviar / desvio (noun)",
    "id": 626672991,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "resourceful (she's a very resourceful manager) / resourcefulness",
    "back": "engenhoso, criativo, cheio de recursos (adj.) / engenhosidade, criatividade (noun)",
    "id": 433791722,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "odds (If you drive a car all your life, the odds are that you'll have an accident at some point / The overall odds of winning a lottery prize are 1 in 13)",
    "back": "probabilidade, chances",
    "id": 136088478,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "one–off (Will you be doing more talks in the future or was that just a one–off? / They gave him a one–off payment to compensate for the extra hours that he had to work)",
    "back": "algo que acontece apenas uma vez (noun / adj.)",
    "id": 678831619,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "outbreak (after a zika outbreak)",
    "back": "surto",
    "id": 261820812,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "stuntman (Assassin’s Creed stuntman perform a monstrous 125 foot leap of faith)",
    "back": "dublê",
    "id": 733085976,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "gunpoint (they were robbed at gunpoint)",
    "back": "mão armada (eles foram assaltados à mão armada)",
    "id": 685357467,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "underpants (Are you wearing underpants)",
    "back": "cueca, calcinha",
    "id": 581618675,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "mistrust / distrust (I've always mistrusted politicians)",
    "back": "desconfiar / desconfiança (mis e dis são sinônimos)",
    "id": 750079363,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "default (he is defaulting on his loans) / (defaults on loan repayments have reached 52,000 a month)",
    "back": "deixar de pagar (verb) / falhas de pagamento (noun)",
    "id": 467973161,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "whistleblower (The Pentagon's most famous whistleblower is Foo) / blow the whistle (I will blow the whistle)",
    "back": "denunciante (noun) / denunciar",
    "id": 295712768,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "settle (They haven't yet settled when the wedding is going to be / After they got married, they settled in Brooklyn)",
    "back": "resolver, decidir, estabelecer / viver, morar",
    "id": 216711556,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "disgusting (It's disgusting that there are no schools or hospitals for these people)",
    "back": "repugnante, nojento, desagradável",
    "id": 235599208,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "outcome (It's too early to predict the outcome of the meeting)",
    "back": "resultado, efeito de alguma ação",
    "id": 706363797,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "livestock (this would be the product that feeds the pigs and other livestock throughout the world)",
    "back": "animals and birds that are kept on a farm, such as cows, sheep, or chickens. They are raised for food or money.",
    "id": 759157016,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "acknowledge (you must acknowledge the truth of her argument) / acknowledgment (all I want is some acknowledgment that his behaviour is unreasonable)",
    "back": "reconhecer / reconhecimento, agradecimento",
    "id": 437423829,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "debunk (the writer's aim was to debunk the myth that had grown up around the actress)",
    "back": "mostrar, refutar, desmistificar, desmentir",
    "id": 523454746,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "name–calling (because name–calling does nothing to improve understanding or move the political debate forward)",
    "back": "xingamentos (noun)",
    "id": 792415032,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "let down (I won't let you down)",
    "back": "desapontar, decepcionar",
    "id": 287945154,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "get by (I can get by with my spanish / I know enough to get by / many brazillians get by on one minimum salary /I can get by on 6 hours of sleep / I don't know much about technology, but I can get by at work )",
    "back": "se virar, lidar com situaçao difícil (inclusive sem dinheiro)",
    "id": 316016213,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "haven (there is no safe haven)",
    "back": "refúgio, abrigo",
    "id": 264797238,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "swear in (Michel sworm in as Brazilian President after historic Rousseff impeachment)",
    "back": "fazer juramento de ser leal, empossar (tomar posse).",
    "id": 883147380,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "setback (a rocket failure for any company is going to be a setback)",
    "back": "contratempo, revés",
    "id": 113060050,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "makeover (one of the prizes was a makeover at a top beauty salon)",
    "back": "reforma (numa pessoa ou lugar)",
    "id": 201173148,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "harassment (sexual harassment)",
    "back": "assédio",
    "id": 110458514,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "save on (It was a warm winter, so we saved on electricity)",
    "back": "economizar",
    "id": 711778485,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "by heart (my father can still recite the poems he learned by heart at school / I know the rule by heart)",
    "back": "de cór (coração), da memória",
    "id": 472715907,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "better off (he’d be better off working for a bigger company / you are better off crafting your own style guide)",
    "back": "estar numa situação melhor",
    "id": 110305605,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "on my own (I can drive on my own / Write it on your own)",
    "back": "sozinho, por si próprio, independente (eu posso dirigir sozinho / escreva isso sozinho)",
    "id": 278308921,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "mock (don't mock on me / they were mocking him because he kept falling off his bike) (mock leather)",
    "back": "zombar (não me zombe) / simulado, falso (adj.)",
    "id": 846918760,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "set off (he fears that the election could set off mass protests)",
    "back": "desencadear (to cause a situation or a series of events to happen, especially without intending to)",
    "id": 765787171,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "harm (thankfully no one was harmed in the accident / the government's reputation has already been harmed by a series of scandals)",
    "back": "machucar alguém ou prejudicar/danificar algo",
    "id": 472954632,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "strict (my parents were very strict with us)",
    "back": "rígido, severo, rigoroso",
    "id": 711312414,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "loose (two lions escaped and are still loose / a giant moon balloon got loose in China / a loose dress)",
    "back": "solto, frouxo/largo (adj.) (um balão gigante se soltou na China / um vestido frouxo/largo)",
    "id": 788582940,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "naked (you are totally naked)",
    "back": "nu, sem defesa, desamparado",
    "id": 653112105,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "cargo (what is the cargo in the ship?)",
    "back": "carga, carregamento",
    "id": 401626307,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "breach (there have been serious security breaches / their defences were easily breached.)",
    "back": "brecha, violação (noun) / violar, romper",
    "id": 589557367,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "blueprint (below is their suggested blueprint for how to protect yourself)",
    "back": "modelo, desenho técnico, diagrama",
    "id": 197106501,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "swear word (the science of swear words)",
    "back": "palavrão",
    "id": 511161779,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "swear word (the science of swear words)",
    "back": "palavrão",
    "id": 644424921,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "other way around",
    "back": "ao contrário",
    "id": 243233886,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "friction (politics is a source of considerable friction in our family)",
    "back": "atrito",
    "id": 469646597,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "think up (I don't want to go tonight but I can't think up a good excuse)",
    "back": "inventar (idéia ou plano)",
    "id": 254888430,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "charge (She's been charged)",
    "back": "acusar (ela foi acusada) / acusação",
    "id": 169295190,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "beat (Did Hillary beat Trump / Yes, Hillary beat Trump)",
    "back": "vencer (alguém), no passado também é beat. Win = vencer, porém não quando se fala que fulano venceu ciclano. Ex: Who won the debate yesterday?. Forma errada: Hillary won Trump (certo aqui é beat)",
    "id": 250708816,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "come across as/like (diferente de apenas 'come across') (I'm sorry if what I said came across as criticism / Hillary needs to come across like softer, gentler / What do I come across as?)",
    "back": "parecer, passar/dar a impressão de ser (me desculpe se o que eu disse pareceu uma crítica / ela precisa se parecer mais suave, mais gentil / O que eu passo a impressão de ser?)",
    "id": 889412163,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "crack down (on someone/something) (the library is cracking down on people who lose their books / He's cracking down on drug crime) / crackdown (noun) (a crackdown on crime and corruption)",
    "back": "ser severo, pegar firme/duro (em relação algum comportamento mal ou ilegal) (Ele está pegando firme com os crimes de drogas) / repressão",
    "id": 374011611,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "piece of news / news story (I came across a piece of news / I came across a news story)",
    "back": "uma notícia em específico (news é incontável, usa para notícia em geral)",
    "id": 158584560,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "some 32.000 people have been arrested",
    "back": "cerca de 32.000 pessoas foram presas",
    "id": 163518637,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "account (She gave a thrilling account of her life in the jungle)",
    "back": "relato",
    "id": 542984550,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "cast out (the perfect love casts out fear)",
    "back": "expulsar",
    "id": 338719331,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "piece of furniture / furniture piece / item of furniture  (how a forgotten piece of furniture found a second life / the 9 best furniture pieces for every type of home)",
    "back": "móvel em específico (furniture é móveis em geral)",
    "id": 320854428,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "shelter (they opened a shelter to provide temporary housing for the city's homeless / A group of us were sheltering from the rain under the trees)",
    "back": "abrigo, abrigar",
    "id": 625404360,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "thick (as the atmosphere gets thicker..) / thin (thinner)",
    "back": "grosso (conforme a atmosfera fica mais grossa) / fino (mais fino)",
    "id": 571292719,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "piece of software / computer program / software application (10 pieces of software that changed the world)",
    "back": "um software em específico (apenas 'software' é muito geral)",
    "id": 634686421,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "passerby (a passer–by saw smoke and called the fire department)",
    "back": "transeunte (plural: passersby)",
    "id": 669943864,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "lawsuit (they filed a lawsuit against the company)",
    "back": "ação judicial (noun)",
    "id": 150498829,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "outweigh (the benefits of this treatment far outweigh any risks)",
    "back": "prevalecer sobre, pesar mais que (weigh = pesar)",
    "id": 755956185,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "gag (He was gagged and left in a cell for three days / Her hands and feet were tied and a gag placed over her mouth)",
    "back": "amordaçar (verb) / mordaça (noun)",
    "id": 408486809,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "countryside (The countryside around there is beautiful)",
    "back": "campo (terra no campo), zona rural",
    "id": 439964897,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "like–minded (they caught the attention of some like–minded friends)",
    "back": "de mesma opinião (adj.) (eles chamaram atenção de alguns amigos de mesma opinião)",
    "id": 587009014,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "beef up (Merkel wants to beef up sanctions against Russia: newspaper)",
    "back": "fortalecer, reforçar",
    "id": 433911027,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "worse off (Are you better off today or are you worse off?)",
    "back": "pior",
    "id": 848982391,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "rough up (He was roughed up by a gang of youths)",
    "back": "espancar, bater",
    "id": 673353221,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "take on (five new ways Google is taking on Apple I’ll take you on in a game of chess / She took on the task of indexing the book)",
    "back": "competir, lutar (com algo ou alguém) / assumir",
    "id": 834029079,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "dull (in Ruby we don't have to write all of those dull methods)",
    "back": "maçante (adj.), entediante",
    "id": 163490804,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "grasp (I can grasp this code; it is hard to grasp some concepts / you will have a better grasp..)",
    "back": "compreender / compreensão",
    "id": 794804983,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "tap into (the company is hoping to tap into the chinese market / If only we could tap into all that energy and creativity)",
    "back": "explorar, usar (algo para benefício)",
    "id": 895807255,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "reportedly (Turkey has reportedly blocked Twitter, Facebook and WhatsApp nationwide)",
    "back": "segundo notícias, supostamente (alguém disse, não necessariamente é verdade)",
    "id": 524026980,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "undereducated (he is undereducated)",
    "back": "pobremente ou insuficientemente educado (adj.)",
    "id": 539448744,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "remarkable (Nelson Mandela was a truly remarkable man)",
    "back": "notável (adj.)",
    "id": 746979360,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pledge (we are asking people to pledge their support for our campaign / thousands of people made pledges to the charity campaign)",
    "back": "prometer / promessa (de dar dinheiro inclusive)",
    "id": 714690437,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "cripple (you teach crippled children yoga / higher taxes could cripple small businesses)",
    "back": "aleijar, aleijado (adj, noun) / prejudicar seriamente",
    "id": 645807502,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "no–brainer (the math test was a no–brainer!)",
    "back": "moleza, muito fácil (a prova de matemática foi moleza)",
    "id": 213820989,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "appoint (we've appointed three new teachers this year / A date has been appointed for the election)",
    "back": "nomear, definir uma data",
    "id": 437506272,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "to boo (Pence got booed)",
    "back": "vaiar (Pence foi vaiado)",
    "id": 478745071,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "Christmas is 47 days away",
    "back": "restam 47 dias para o Natal",
    "id": 606708166,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "thankful (I am thankful for all my friends / What are you thankful for?)",
    "back": "ser grato por algo (adj) (estou grato/agradecido por todos meus amigos)",
    "id": 615219848,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "deceive (I dont want to deceive you)",
    "back": "enganar, iludir",
    "id": 545076190,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "housekeeper (Ana is a great housekeeper)",
    "back": "empregada doméstica",
    "id": 652985685,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "budget (PineBook is a budget laptop)",
    "back": "barato (adj) / orçar (verb) / orçamento (noun)",
    "id": 165010209,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "wake–up call (this is a wake–up call)",
    "back": "aviso (isso é um aviso)",
    "id": 707535547,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "lame (the new Harry Potter movie is pretty lame)",
    "back": "fraco, insatisfatório (I don't want to hear your lame excuses)",
    "id": 813694697,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pork (I'm allergic to pork!)",
    "back": "carne de porco (porco morto) / pig é o animal, vivo",
    "id": 447023436,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "track record (you have the ability and the track record to get things done)",
    "back": "histórico (trajetória)",
    "id": 450829220,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "put off (what are you putting off? / I've put off talking to him)",
    "back": "adiar, postergar, deixar para depois (colocar 'ing' no verbo apos 'put off')",
    "id": 858052209,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "flagship (the flagship phone / The company's flagship store is in New York)",
    "back": "melhor ou mais importante produto, idéia ou prédio que uma organização tem ou produz",
    "id": 322781641,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "shot dead (Female journalist Eman Salehi, 28, was shot dead in the street on 23 December)",
    "back": "morto a tiros",
    "id": 523110573,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "thrive (his business thrived in the years before the war)",
    "back": "prosperar (verb)",
    "id": 753506379,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "amend (until the constitution is amended, the power to appoint ministers will remain with the president)",
    "back": "emendar (reformar, corrigir uma lei ou texto)",
    "id": 740340437,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "amendment (presidential power was reduced by a constitutional amendment in 1991)",
    "back": "emenda, reforma (de uma lei ou texto) (noun)",
    "id": 792885904,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "get a grip (I just think he ought to get a grip on himself – he's behaving like a child)",
    "back": "controlar as emoções (se controlar)",
    "id": 468778097,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pick up (I need to pick up my parents / When you're in town could you pick up the books I ordered?)",
    "back": "buscar, pegar algo ou alguém",
    "id": 224331290,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "turn down (He was turned down for the job because of insufficient experience)",
    "back": "recusar, rejeitar",
    "id": 141928583,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "scattered (my family is scattered all over the world)",
    "back": "espalhado, disperso (adj.)",
    "id": 622316372,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "dizzy (Don't you get dizzy this way?)",
    "back": "tonto (adj) / entontecer",
    "id": 427572810,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pull out (our company is pulling out of the personal computer business) / (the truck pulled out in front of me)",
    "back": "sair, retirar–se (atividade, situação ou evento) / entrar com veiculo numa faixa (o caminhão entrou na minha frente)",
    "id": 698558198,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "upscale / upmarket (upscale restaurant)",
    "back": "de luxo (restaurante de luxo)",
    "id": 839167931,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "disrepair (the house was in a bad state of disrepair)",
    "back": "ruina (noun)",
    "id": 805011985,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "você arrasou (mandou bem)",
    "back": "you rocked, you nailed it, you killed it",
    "id": 370932326,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "backlash (Trump's travel ban sparks global backlash)",
    "back": "repercussão (noun)",
    "id": 883400043,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "out loud (please read it out loud)",
    "back": "em voz alta",
    "id": 774621911,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "aide (former Trump aide says US will pull out of Paris climate deal within days)",
    "back": "assessor",
    "id": 248311318,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "work out (my car broke down; but don’t worry, it’ll all work out)",
    "back": "dar certo (it will all work out = tudo vai dar certo)",
    "id": 355180674,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "try on (I tried on a t–shirt, but it was too large)",
    "back": "experimentar (roupa)",
    "id": 421125714,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "comeback (did you watch the super bowl last night? What an amazing comeback and win by the patriots! / Down 28 – 03, the Patriots came back to beat the Falcons!)",
    "back": "virada / virar (placar, jogo) (perdendo de 28 – 03, os Patriotas viraram e venceram os Falcons)",
    "id": 320254831,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "caveat (He agreed to the interview, with the caveat that he could approve the final article)",
    "back": "ressalva",
    "id": 209856900,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "blackmail (they used the photographs to blackmail her)",
    "back": "chantagear / chantagem",
    "id": 651384177,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "outstanding (Couch is outstanding at aggregation.. // there are still a couple of problems outstanding)",
    "back": "excepcional (adj) / não pago/resolvido/feito ($450 million in outstanding debts)",
    "id": 557923024,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "on purpose (I didn’t do it on purpose – it was an accident)",
    "back": "de propósito",
    "id": 159625535,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "outlaw (I think all handguns should be outlawed / He is a dangerous outlaw)",
    "back": "proibir, tornar ilegal (verb) / fora da lei, criminoso (noun)",
    "id": 562573455,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "paternity leave / maternity leave",
    "back": "licença paternidade / licença maternidade",
    "id": 153869487,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pack up (I’m going to pack my things up and go home)",
    "back": "empacotar algo / fazer as malas (verb)",
    "id": 228822931,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pack up (I’m going to pack my things up and go home)",
    "back": "empacotar algo / fazer as malas (verb)",
    "id": 175305014,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pack up (I’m going to pack my things up and go home)",
    "back": "empacotar algo / fazer as malas (verb)",
    "id": 754275961,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "wiretap (the court gave permission to have his phone wiretapped to gather evidence)",
    "back": "grampear / grampo (noun)",
    "id": 510052491,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "creepy (a creepy insect)",
    "back": "arrepiante, rastejante",
    "id": 843129993,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "overreact (please try not to overreact if she drives badly when she is first learning)",
    "back": "exagerar",
    "id": 469997400,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "this big (my dog is about this big [40 cm])",
    "back": "desse tamanho (meu cachorro é mais ou menos desse tamanho)",
    "id": 689538415,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "mate (she is in season, she needs to mate)",
    "back": "acasalar (ele está no sil, ela precisa acasalar)",
    "id": 668165294,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "was told (I was told I could buy a ticket here)",
    "back": "me disseram (que eu poderia comprar uma passagem/bilhete aqui)",
    "id": 693668840,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "mastermind (Russian agents accused by US of masterminding Yahoo hack)",
    "back": "planejar, organizar, ser o cérebro (geralmente de um crime) / cérebro (noun)",
    "id": 565529410,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "kingpin (he is the kingpin)",
    "back": "chefão, líder de uma organização",
    "id": 721200984,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "embolden (emboldened by drink, he walked over to speak to her)",
    "back": "encorajar (encorajado por bebida, ele caminhou pra falar com ela)",
    "id": 732362799,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "come up (I was going to play soccer yesterday, but something came up, so, I came back home)",
    "back": "surgir (imprevisto) (eu estava indo jogar futebol ontem mas surgiu algo, então, tive que voltar pra casa)",
    "id": 762883347,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "on the verge (the scientists are on the verge of making an important breakthrough)",
    "back": "à beira, estar preste a fazer algo (os cientistas estão à beira de fazer um importante avanço)",
    "id": 415463748,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "painkiller (a lot of painkillers have turned out to be addictive substances for patients)",
    "back": "analgésico",
    "id": 850953565,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "to spare (just two votes to spare)",
    "back": "de sobra, a mais (apenas dois votos de sobra)",
    "id": 211613473,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "stop by (can we stop by McDonalds? / why don’t you stop by sometime for lunch?)",
    "back": "parar, passar, aparecer (podemos parar no McDonalds? / pq você não aparece qualquer hora pra almoçar?)",
    "id": 641469977,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "shortfall (they are facing an expected $10 billion shortfall in revenue)",
    "back": "défice",
    "id": 851463103,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "(to be) short of (I’m short of money! Would you buy me lunch?)",
    "back": "faltar/não ter algo ou ter insuficiente (estou com pouco grana. Você me paga o almoço?)",
    "id": 374917348,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "piss off (don’t piss me off!)",
    "back": "irritar (não me irrite)",
    "id": 200145279,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "masterpiece (The Ethics of Liberty is a masterpiece of argumentation)",
    "back": "obra–prima",
    "id": 337466507,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pass out (I don’t remember any more because I passed out)",
    "back": "desmaiar",
    "id": 583846465,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "cheer up (Cheer up. It’s not the end of the world!)",
    "back": "anime–se",
    "id": 276297363,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "laughingstock (Trump was the laughingstock of NATO)",
    "back": "chacota (noun), ridicularizado",
    "id": 615033858,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "savory (do you prefer sweet or savory food?)",
    "back": "salgada (você prefere comida doce ou salgada?)",
    "id": 758712711,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bombshell (my sister dropped a bombshell by announcing she was leaving her job)",
    "back": "bomba (noun) (notícia repentina e geralmente não agradável) / uma pessoa bonita (a blonde bombshell)",
    "id": 557098014,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "collude (Did Trump collude with Russia?) / collusion (Jeff denies collusion with Russia)",
    "back": "conspirar (verb) (Trump conspirou com a Russia?) / conspiração (noun) (Jeff nega conspiração com a Russia)",
    "id": 221142919,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "juicy (juicy apples)",
    "back": "suculento (adj) (maças suculentas)",
    "id": 452232376,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "gunfire (explosions and gunfire reported at Istanbul's Airport)",
    "back": "tiroteiro (noun)",
    "id": 686141088,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "lollipop",
    "back": "pirulito",
    "id": 782294651,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "walk–in (a walk–in clinic)",
    "back": "um serviço available for customers or clients without the need for an appointment (não precisa marcar, só entrar)",
    "id": 758587364,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "change (here is your change, sir, keep the change)",
    "back": "troco (aqui está seu troco senhor, fique com o troco)",
    "id": 846371328,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "stinks (wow, that bathroom stinks! / the kitchen stinks of fish)",
    "back": "feder (cheia muito mal) / fedor (noun)",
    "id": 797423571,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "steak (enjoy this juicy steak)",
    "back": "bife, filé (carne, peixe) (aprecie esse bife suculento)",
    "id": 352005239,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "garlic (add the crushed garlic clove)",
    "back": "alho (crushed garlic clove = dente de alho amassado)",
    "id": 631845376,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "leftover / left over (we have leftover spaghetti for lunch today / there’s some pasta left over)",
    "back": "resto, sobra (temos sobra de spaghetti para almoço hoje)",
    "id": 199091997,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "show off (he drives expensive cars to show off his wealth)",
    "back": "exibir, ostentar",
    "id": 324647976,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "luggage (I label my luggage when I travel)",
    "back": "bagagem",
    "id": 123885666,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "up for (are you up for studying English tonight?) (informal)",
    "back": "estar afim (vc está afim de estudar inglês hoje?)",
    "id": 404709815,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "jerk (my friend is not a jerk; he is actually a nice guy)",
    "back": "idiota",
    "id": 179393063,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "anthem (everyone stood to sing the national anthem)",
    "back": "hino",
    "id": 651915497,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "get–together (my family had a nice get–together for Independence Day in Brazil)",
    "back": "reunião (noun) / reunir–se (my family gets together for Christmas)",
    "id": 586917703,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "crybaby (you are a crybaby)",
    "back": "chorão",
    "id": 161364949,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "hassle (tips and advice for a hassle–free holiday)",
    "back": "aborrecimento, incômodo, problema (noun)",
    "id": 798249698,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "sloppy (this work is sloppy; it's full of errors)",
    "back": "negligente, descuidado (adj)",
    "id": 375981459,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "inmate (the inmate's wife came to visit him in prison)",
    "back": "detento, preso (noun)",
    "id": 610052246,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "brag (my dad likes to brag when he catches a big fish)",
    "back": "se gabar (verb)",
    "id": 587002455,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bill (after work, the waiter counted the bills and coins)",
    "back": "nota (de dinheiro)",
    "id": 148923104,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "feasible (my ideal was good, but it was not feasible in practice)",
    "back": "viável, exequível",
    "id": 446091402,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "out of the blue (I hate to turn up out of the blue uninvited)",
    "back": "do nada, repentinamente (eu odeio aparecer do nada sem ser convidada)",
    "id": 800673252,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "overstate (the impact of the new legislation has been greatly overstated)",
    "back": "exagerar, superestimar (verb)",
    "id": 650347293,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "check in (I'm just checking in to say hello)",
    "back": "'passar' (eu só estou passando pra dizer oi)",
    "id": 309038815,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "wager (you must place an initial wager)",
    "back": "aposta, apostar",
    "id": 270331905,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bedtime (it's bedtime)",
    "back": "hora de dormir",
    "id": 463885291,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "filthy (the conservative lady considered the book obscene and filthy)",
    "back": "imundo, sujo (adj.)",
    "id": 182412965,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "kick in (you’ll feel better when the medicine kicks in)",
    "back": "fazer efeito, entrar em vigor (verb)",
    "id": 279513888,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "jackass (you are a jackass)",
    "back": "jumento (animal) / burro, idiota",
    "id": 176261193,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "fart (Carson farted on TV)",
    "back": "peidar, peido (noun)",
    "id": 660945924,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "manpower (we will have more time and manpower)",
    "back": "mão de obra",
    "id": 871966474,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "fierce (the battle is going to be fierce)",
    "back": "feroz (adj)",
    "id": 235418164,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "ditch (the group ditched the idea because it was impractical)",
    "back": "abandonar / dispensar",
    "id": 406345314,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "live up (it's hard to live up to the same level of success that my dad had)",
    "back": "fazer jus à, corresponder, estar a altura (é difícil corresponder ao mesmo nível de sucesso que meu pai teve)",
    "id": 262888852,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "make a point (I always make a point to say hello)",
    "back": "fazer questão / frisar (eu sempre faço questão de dizer oi)",
    "id": 555637470,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "rip–off (noun) (have you seen the prices of the Mac Pro? What a rip–off!)",
    "back": "roubo (forma de dizer algo muito caro)",
    "id": 154300647,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "rub in (you beat me at chess. You don’t need to rub it in)",
    "back": "esfregar na cara (rub in – verb) / jogar na cara",
    "id": 601345210,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "never mind (could you help me install this program? Oh, never mind, I already did it)",
    "back": "deixa pra lá, não se preocupe (would you mind? = vc se importaria?)",
    "id": 756433669,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "rule out (the president has ruled out the use of US troops)",
    "back": "descartar (verb)",
    "id": 186837624,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "come to think of it (come to think of it. I forgive them)",
    "back": "pensando bem",
    "id": 260797038,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "coming along (how is the drumming going? It’s coming along)",
    "back": "está indo (progredindo) (como está indo a bateria? Está indo)",
    "id": 227759314,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "it is a shame (it's a shame what they do with these dogs)",
    "back": "é uma pena / é uma vergonha",
    "id": 371726225,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "up in arms (the Democrats are up in arms about what the attorney–general said)",
    "back": "em pé de guerra / revoltado (os Democratas estão em pé de guerra sobre oq o advogado geral disse)",
    "id": 612874967,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "get cracking (we can get a flow agreed with Gareth and you can get cracking on building the integration)",
    "back": "começar a fazer algo imediatamente (informal)",
    "id": 256245239,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "lash out (they lash out with no concern for others and promote fear to justify stricter controls)",
    "back": "atacar de repente algo ou alguém / criticar (eles atacam sem consideração por outros..)",
    "id": 806247241,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "in spite of (I went for a walk in spite of the bad weather)",
    "back": "apesar de (eu sai para andar apesar do mau tempo)",
    "id": 104634878,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "role model (the teacher was a role model for her students)",
    "back": "a person looked to by others as an example to be imitated.",
    "id": 499358177,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "ill will (I do so with no ill will)",
    "back": "má vontade",
    "id": 533741376,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "flip side (we're now starting to see the flip side of the government's economic policy)",
    "back": "the opposite, less good, or less popular side of something",
    "id": 829795188,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "cope with (we need to cope with the changes)",
    "back": "lidar com (nós precisamos lidar com as alterações)",
    "id": 380035914,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "chip in (everyone chipped in for the gift)",
    "back": "contribuir (todos contribuiram para o presente)",
    "id": 455622572,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "see off (we saw our friends off at the airport yesterday)",
    "back": "despedir (nós despedimos de nossos amigos no aeroporto ontem)",
    "id": 391091525,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "on the loose (lions on the loose)",
    "back": "à solta (leões à solta)",
    "id": 340716658,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "set apart (I set apart some money for my trip)",
    "back": "separar (eu separei algum dinheiro para minha viagem)",
    "id": 734045512,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "skid (Tony's car skidded on some ice and hit a tree)",
    "back": "derrapar, derrapagem (o carro do Tony derrapou no gelo e atingiu uma arvore)",
    "id": 153152145,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "dress up (you can dress up mannequins for display. When customers see them, they'll come in)",
    "back": "vestir elegantemente",
    "id": 242041794,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "as though (On the other hand, we must not behave as though nothing has happened)",
    "back": "como se (..como se nada 'tivesse' acontecido)",
    "id": 344950113,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "sleep around (if you sleep around, you increase your risk of getting AIDS / I never knew she was the kind that sleeps around)",
    "back": "have many casual sexual partners (termo pejorativo)",
    "id": 724112274,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "go out of [pronoum] way (she really went out of her way to get you this job interview)",
    "back": "se esforçar, fazer o possível (ela realmente se esforçou para conseguir essa entrevista de emprego para voce)",
    "id": 209144390,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "whatchamacallit (I need a whatchamacallit, you know that thing you use to pay)",
    "back": "coisa / algo que vc nao lembra o nome (eu preciso de uma coisa, vc sabe aquela coisa usada para pagar)",
    "id": 321610809,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "homage (As an homage to the Terminal, we liked the idea of naming the font after its codename)",
    "back": "homenagem",
    "id": 697247476,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "dodge (Boris dodges questions on brexit)",
    "back": "esquivar (verb)",
    "id": 697662039,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "scare to death (I am scared to death of cats / my sister is scared to death of cats)",
    "back": "'morre de medo' – usar com verbo to be (eu morro de medo de gatos / minha irmã morre de medo de gatos)",
    "id": 892703109,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "slam (he slammed China on Twitter when LeBron was on his way to China)",
    "back": "criticar (informal) – (ele criticou China no Twitter enquanto LeBron estava indo pra China)",
    "id": 427895355,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "well–off, well off (my parents were well–off / now I’m well–off; I have my own room)",
    "back": "rico, bem de vida, abundante (não apenas em dinheiro)",
    "id": 393589258,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "wary (dogs that have been mistreated often remain very wary of strangers)",
    "back": "cauteloso, atento",
    "id": 150180813,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "ripple effect (it has a ripple effect throughout the economy)",
    "back": "efeito cascata (isso tem um efeito cascata por toda a economia)",
    "id": 410490185,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "get on (can we please get on, because there are a lot of things still to discuss)",
    "back": "continuar, progredir (nós podemos continuar por favor, pq há muitas coisas ainda a discutir)",
    "id": 127297265,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "cut corners (the product is made with inferior materials to cut corners on costs)",
    "back": "economizar (o produto é feito com materiais inferiores para economizar custos) / pegar atalhos",
    "id": 149786304,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "crave (they promise people the things they crave)",
    "back": "almejar (eles prometem as pessoas coisas que eles almejam) / desejar",
    "id": 342167124,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "spook (it's extremely easy to spook this fish)",
    "back": "assustar (é extremamente fácil assustar esse peixe) / fantasma (mesmo que ghost) / espião (a CIA spook)",
    "id": 559811485,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "jump the gun (some booksellers have jumped the gun and decided to sell it early)",
    "back": "to act too soon or before the right time (alguns vendedores de livros se anteciparam e decidiram vender isso mais cedo)",
    "id": 225802262,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "laughter (her laughter filled the place with joy) – lê–se 'láfter'",
    "back": "riso, risos, risada (o riso dela encheu o lugar de alegria) – noun",
    "id": 884010305,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "convicted (that man is a convicted terrorist)",
    "back": "condenado (aquele homem é um terrorista condenado)",
    "id": 836904687,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "keen (both had keen scientific minds)",
    "back": "aguçado – adj. (ambos tinham mentes científicas aguçadas)",
    "id": 203607465,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "dismay (to his dismay, she left him)",
    "back": "desânimo / desanimar (para seu desânimo, ela o deixou)",
    "id": 609143601,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "peel (NOUN: remove the orange peel and cut it into thin strips / VERB: I started the recipe by peeling the potatoes)",
    "back": "casca (remova a casca da laranja e corte–a em tiras finas) / descascar (eu comecei a receita descascando as batatas)",
    "id": 345432906,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "flattered (I am flattered you want to talk to me) / flatter",
    "back": "lisonjeado (adj) / lisonjear (verb)",
    "id": 629736831,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "go by (a couple moments go by and I feel something)",
    "back": "passar (alguns momentos se passam e eu sinto algo)",
    "id": 637783510,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "oblivious (people still remain oblivious to what happened yesterday)",
    "back": "alheio, não ciente (adj)",
    "id": 527980231,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "cave in (help me, it's like the walls are caving in)",
    "back": "desmoronar [verb] (ajude me, é como se as paredes estivessem desmoronando)",
    "id": 128833396,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "just off (the island is just off the coast of Florida)",
    "back": "perto de",
    "id": 656370857,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "raffle (the first prize in the raffle is a trip to Miami)",
    "back": "rifa (o primeiro prêmio na rifa é uma viagem pra Miami)",
    "id": 715380532,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "boast (the student likes to boast of his grades / it may sound like a boast, but I truly am very wealthy)",
    "back": "gabar, orgulhar (o estudante gosta de se gabar de suas notas) / ostentação [noun]",
    "id": 792972836,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "makeshift (he arranged a row of chairs to form a makeshift bed)",
    "back": "improvisado (adj, noun)",
    "id": 782330339,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "bad–mouth (no one wants to hire an individual who bad–mouths a prior employer)",
    "back": "criticar, falar mal (he is a bad–mouther)",
    "id": 597001463,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "either one (coffee or tea? Either one, I like both)",
    "back": "qualquer um, tanto faz",
    "id": 613510355,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "be down to (once the strategy is decided, it will be down to authorities to implement it)",
    "back": "to be someone's responsibility or decision (uma vez que a estratégia estiver definida, CABERÁ as autoridades implementar ela)",
    "id": 823280788,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "nod (I see people nodding)",
    "back": "acenar com a cabeça [verb] (para cumprimentar ou dizer que 'sim')",
    "id": 725502965,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "downplay (Trump downplayed the impact of the U.S. coronavirus outbreak on Twitter this week)",
    "back": "minimizar / subestimar (Trump minimizou o impacto do surto de coronavirus no Twitter essa semana)",
    "id": 556244253,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "strain (I feel under strain when I speak in public)",
    "back": "tensão / pressão (eu sinto sob pressão quando eu falo em publico)",
    "id": 650065803,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "at times (at times, I forget to lock the door when I leave)",
    "back": "as vezes (as vezes, eu esqueço de trancar a porta quando eu saio)",
    "id": 603033865,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "weighted (what is the weighted average of this?)",
    "back": "ponderado [adj] (qual a média ponderada disso?)",
    "id": 482584470,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "flat out (they worked flat out on this project / the idea was rejected flat out)",
    "back": "a todo vapor / com afinco",
    "id": 398516062,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "soar (It’s not just Zoom,” he said, referring to the video conferencing company whose shares have soared 130% this year)",
    "back": "subir, planar (voar)",
    "id": 831126794,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "hang in there",
    "back": "aguenta firme",
    "id": 775854358,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "halfway through (I am halfway through the book 'War and Peace')",
    "back": "na metade / no meio (estou na metade do livro War and Peace)",
    "id": 312043887,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "steadfast (the president remained steadfast against pressure from the unions)",
    "back": "firme (o presidente se manteve firme contra a pressão dos sindicatos)",
    "id": 241434902,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "get the hang of something (I’ll teach you how to use the design program, you’ll get the hang of it after a while.)",
    "back": "pegar o jeito (vou te ensinar a usar o programa de design, vc vai pegar o jeito depois de um tempo)",
    "id": 189598996,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "flea market (there is a flea market every Sunday)",
    "back": "a street market selling second–hand goods",
    "id": 888794255,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "grim (another grim milestone, more than 2000 people have died of coronavirus)",
    "back": "sombrio / cruel / sinistro (adj)",
    "id": 832699314,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "stem from (his love of the outdoors stems from his father.)",
    "back": "vir de algo ou alguem / ser causado por algo ou alguem (seu amor pelo ar livre vem de seu pai)",
    "id": 495932909,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "downturn (despite the downturn, the economy will soon recover)",
    "back": "declínio, desacelaração (apesar da desaceleração, a economia vai se recuperar em breve) [noun]",
    "id": 300644039,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "silver lining (finding a silver lining in quarantine)",
    "back": "lado bom de algo (encontrando o lado bom na quarentena)",
    "id": 359206628,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "watered–down (USO has become a watered–down version of its former self)",
    "back": "diluido, atenuado, enfraquecido (USO se tornou uma versão diluida de sua forma antiga) [adj]",
    "id": 522542645,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "to third wheel (he was third wheeling / he was the third wheel)",
    "back": "ficar de vela (ele estava ficando de vela), vela (ele foi a vela)",
    "id": 847458535,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "upbringing (Paul had a strict upbringing)",
    "back": "educação, criação, formação (Paul teve uma educação rígida)",
    "id": 785682644,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "peace out ",
    "back": "falou / tchau",
    "id": 817570586,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "shut off (can you shut off the tv please?)",
    "back": "desligar / fechar (torneira)",
    "id": 135903250,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "plunge (the kids immediately plunged into the pool / markets are plunging today)",
    "back": "mergulhar, submerger, cair [verb] / mergulho [noun]",
    "id": 107636565,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "feel bad for (I feel bad for little mice. I don’t like to kill them)",
    "back": "ter dó de algo (eu tenho dó dos ratinhos, eu não gosto de matar eles) (mice = plural de rato)",
    "id": 894328262,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "shirt on (I have a blue shirt on / I’m recording this podcast without a shirt on)",
    "back": "(eu estou com uma camisa azul / estou gravando esse podcast sem camisa)",
    "id": 525753680,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "offhand (I can't think of a better answer offhand)",
    "back": "sem pensamento prévio ('de cabeça')",
    "id": 575366799,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "up against (up against no deal we accept this deal)",
    "back": "contra (contra nenhum acordo, nós aceitamos esse acordo)",
    "id": 328932471,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "live up (we are just trying to live it up)",
    "back": "aproveitar, aproveitar (nós só estamos tentando apreciar)",
    "id": 794540896,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "slim down (this a slimmed down version of that other PR)",
    "back": "emagrecer, reduzir (esta é uma versão reduzida do outro PR)",
    "id": 203451971,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "dodgy (this business seems pretty dodgy)",
    "back": "duvidoso, não confiável",
    "id": 774272539,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "fishy (how super–rich turn fishy money into empty apartments)",
    "back": "suspeito / desonesto",
    "id": 418619867,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "freakout (the next time you find yourself in the middle of a freakout)",
    "back": "surto",
    "id": 751427790,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "close call (my son almost got hit by a bus. It was a close call!)",
    "back": "por um triz (meu filho quase foi atropelado por um onibus. Foi por um triz.",
    "id": 252168901,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "rosy (the strategy has produced results beyond the most rosy forecasts)",
    "back": "esperançoso, rosado",
    "id": 545650630,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "pop out (I have to pop out for a bit to register Sofia at a kindergarden for next year)",
    "back": "to leave (some place) for a brief period of time.",
    "id": 279460100,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "happen to (do you happen to know my teacher?)",
    "back": "por acaso (vc por acaso conhece meu professor?)",
    "id": 118268975,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "unruly (the unruly boy refused to obey his parents)",
    "back": "indisciplinado",
    "id": 397586291,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "play up (this is just exporter playing up as usual)",
    "back": "se comportar mal / dar trabalho (informal)",
    "id": 627231488,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "to nail down (we finally nail down a routine that we love)",
    "back": "resolver / chegar a um acordo",
    "id": 735097423,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "store clerk (I went to a toy store and asked the store clerk where the Arnold Schwarzenegger Action Figurines were. She Replied: 'Aisle B, Back')",
    "back": "balconista",
    "id": 259004615,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "to draw (winners will be drawn soon)",
    "back": "sortear (vencedores serão sorteados em breve) [esse verbo tbm significa outras coisas, ver outro card]",
    "id": 671591295,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "hectic (thanks again for all the hard work yesterday sounds like things are pretty hectic)",
    "back": "frenético (parece que as coisas estão bem frenéticas)",
    "id": 809865425,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "grow tired (Joe grew tired of his job)",
    "back": "se cansar (Joe se cansou do seu emprego)",
    "id": 475879749,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "run in (singing runs in our family.)",
    "back": "é de família (cantar é de família)",
    "id": 717935688,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "how else (how else may i assist you?)",
    "back": "De que outra forma..",
    "id": 687967670,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "shoehorn (this tiny restaurant is shoehorned between two major banks)",
    "back": "to fit something tightly in a particular place, often between two other things",
    "id": 104874768,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "henceforth (Tech will fix the mappings but only apply it to incoming submissions henceforth)",
    "back": "daqui em diante",
    "id": 378660191,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "how did the rice turn out? / how did the party turn out?",
    "back": "como ficou o arroz? / como foi a festa?",
    "id": 199050496,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "piggyback (everyone wants to piggyback on the phenomenal success of the TV series)",
    "back": "to use something that someone else has made or done in order to get an advantage",
    "id": 583528720,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "jinx (I dont wanna jinx things)",
    "back": "azarar (verb) / azar (noun)",
    "id": 702841235,
    "created_at": "23/10/2022, 14:01:12"
  },
  {
    "front": "make of (well, what did you make of her?)",
    "back": "qual a impressão/opinião/entendimento sobre algo (bem, o que você achou dela)",
    "created_at": "26/10/2022, 14:40:24",
    "id": 1666791624160
  },
  {
    "back": "'cair a ficha' / começar a entender",
    "front": "sink in (the implications of their defeat were beginning to sink in)",
    "created_at": "31/10/2022, 07:29:16",
    "id": 1667201356993
  },
  {
    "front": "grass on (Dan grassed on them to the local police)",
    "back": "dedurar (tell the police or someone in authority about something bad that that person has done)",
    "created_at": "02/11/2022, 12:24:25",
    "id": 1667391865165
  },
  {
    "back": "contar algo a alguem para ouvir a opinião da pessoa (você me falaria sua idea uma vez mais?)",
    "front": "run [something] by [someone] (would you run your idea by me one more time?)",
    "created_at": "08/11/2022, 11:02:04",
    "id": 1667905324202
  },
  {
    "front": "cooking on gas (now that we've had this breakthrough with our experiment, we're really cooking on gas)",
    "back": "to be making rapid progress or performing efficiently",
    "created_at": "13/02/2023, 17:16:15",
    "id": 1676308575068
  },
  {
    "front": "moonlighting (Marcelo and Charles are moonlighting in our tribe for a bit to help out on the user profile work)",
    "back": "have a second job, typically secretly and at night, in addition to one's regular employment.",
    "created_at": "28/03/2023, 11:03:15",
    "id": 1679997795055
  },
  {
    "front": "in anger (have you used GraphQL in anger? Or just for fun?)",
    "back": "\"pra valer\", \"de verdade\" (você já usou GraphQL pra \nvaler? Ou apenas por diversão) ",
    "created_at": "04/04/2023, 21:22:45",
    "id": 1680639765357
  },
  {
    "front": "give or take (8 months give or take)",
    "back": "used to indicate that an amount is approximate. If you say that something is fifty years old, give or take a few years, you mean that it is approximately fifty years old",
    "created_at": "17/04/2023, 10:28:11",
    "id": 1681723691759
  },
  {
    "back": "fazer algo dificil/que vc não quer fazer",
    "front": "bite the bullet (let's bite the bullet and do it)",
    "created_at": "28/04/2023, 15:36:29",
    "id": 1682692589204
  },
  {
    "front": "out of the woods (we are still not out of the woods)",
    "back": "fora de perigo/dificuldades (ainda não estamos sem dificuldades)",
    "created_at": "01/06/2023, 10:38:57",
    "id": 1685612337111
  },
  {
    "back": "atrapalhar / impedir",
    "front": "hinder (price sensitivity may hinder the growth of high-ticket ice cream sales in Brazil)",
    "created_at": "23/06/2023, 13:12:07",
    "id": 1687522327087
  },
  {
    "front": "gutted (we are absolutely gutted with the news)",
    "back": "arrasado (nós estamos absolutamente arrasados com essa noticia)",
    "created_at": "26/01/2024, 10:45:31",
    "id": 1706265931711
  },
  {
    "front": "jazz up (let's add photos to jazz up the dashboards)",
    "back": "to make something more attractive or interesting (vamos adicionar fotos para deixar os dashboards mais atrativos)",
    "created_at": "30/01/2024, 17:54:54",
    "id": 1706637294103
  },
  {
    "back": "rearrajar, organizar diferente (vamos rearranjar os times em breve)",
    "front": "rejig (we gonna rejig the teams soon)",
    "created_at": "09/02/2024, 18:20:10",
    "id": 1707502810508
  },
  {
    "front": "how so? (he claimed innocence, but the evidence suggests otherwise. How so?)",
    "back": "como assim?",
    "created_at": "16/02/2024, 16:52:33",
    "id": 1708102353414
  },
  {
    "back": "tentar algo (deixe tentar arrumar aquilo)",
    "front": "have a stab at [something] (let me have a stab at fixing that)",
    "created_at": "11/03/2024, 16:20:52",
    "id": 1710174052860
  },
  {
    "front": "nitty-gritty (we are going to get into some of the nitty-gritty engineering details)",
    "back": "minucioso",
    "created_at": "23/03/2024, 21:48:45",
    "id": 1711230525764
  },
  {
    "back": "relaxar, descontrair / desenrolar, desbobinar",
    "front": "unwind (can’t wait to unwind with you all!)",
    "created_at": "04/04/2024, 11:26:18",
    "id": 1712226378684
  },
  {
    "front": "back roads (we spent a month with the insurgents on back roads and jungle tracks)",
    "back": "estradas vicinais / estradas rurais (geralmente de terra)",
    "created_at": "25/05/2024, 16:30:30",
    "id": 1716651030343
  },
  {
    "front": "hit on (he was hitting on the girl)",
    "back": "dar em cima (ele estava dando em cima da garota)",
    "created_at": "02/06/2024, 17:33:41",
    "id": 1717346021336
  },
  {
    "front": "sidetrack (sorry we got sidetracked)",
    "back": "desviar (desculpa, nós desviamos [o assunto])",
    "created_at": "14/06/2024, 10:37:13",
    "id": 1718357833672
  },
  {
    "back": "presunçoso / convencido (adjetivo com conotação NEGATIVA)",
    "front": "smug (the France team was very smug)",
    "created_at": "11/07/2024, 13:43:32",
    "id": 1720701812065
  },
  {
    "back": "a partir de (desenvolvemos o plano a partir das diretrizes fornecidas)",
    "front": "off the (we developed the plan off the provided guidelines)",
    "created_at": "18/07/2024, 12:31:08",
    "id": 1721302268352
  },
  {
    "front": "piecemeal (the project is progressing in a slow, piecemeal manner)",
    "back": "pouco a pouco",
    "created_at": "19/07/2024, 21:34:42",
    "id": 1721421282385
  },
  {
    "front": "halve (Germany plans to halve military aid for Ukraine)",
    "back": "cortar pela metade",
    "created_at": "20/07/2024, 15:48:57",
    "id": 1721486937499
  },
  {
    "back": "temer / ter medo (eu estava com medo do voo longo de volta pra casa)",
    "front": "dread (I was dreading the long flight back home)",
    "created_at": "09/08/2024, 14:05:21",
    "id": 1723208721654
  },
  {
    "front": "day in and day out (he works tirelessly, day in and day out, to support his family)",
    "back": "dia após dia",
    "created_at": "09/08/2024, 19:21:49",
    "id": 1723227709929
  },
  {
    "front": "drip by drip, drip feeding",
    "back": "gota a gota",
    "created_at": "17/08/2024, 20:43:44",
    "id": 1723923824454
  },
  {
    "back": "transmitir (as cores no gráfico deven transmitir alguma lógica)",
    "front": "convey (the colors in the chart should convey some logic)",
    "created_at": "26/09/2024, 14:41:33",
    "id": 1727358093125
  },
  {
    "front": "sprinkle (I am going to sprinkle salt over the meat [verb] / a generous sprinkle of pepper [noun])",
    "back": "polvilhar / dar uma pitada (de uma pitada de sal na carne)",
    "created_at": "02/10/2024, 11:56:25",
    "id": 1727866585480
  },
  {
    "front": "predicament (James, you know my predicament)",
    "back": "situação difícil (James, você sabe minha situação difícil)",
    "created_at": "11/10/2024, 10:58:27",
    "id": 1728640707280
  },
  {
    "front": "fiddly (exporting reports to pptx might be fiddly)",
    "back": "complicado (quando há muitas pequenas partes envolvidas)",
    "created_at": "15/10/2024, 11:34:52",
    "id": 1728988492615
  },
  {
    "back": "encolher [fisicamente] / se sentir constrangido/evergonhado (eu me sinto constrangido toda vez que ouço uma dessas frases ridiculas) ",
    "front": "to cringe (I cringe every time I hear one of these ridiculous statements)",
    "created_at": "19/10/2024, 20:42:31",
    "id": 1729366951991
  },
  {
    "back": "quer (informal) [quer outro pedaço de bolo? / quer um pouco de café?]",
    "front": "care for (care for another piece of cake? / care for some coffee)",
    "created_at": "22/10/2024, 09:50:43",
    "id": 1729587043823
  },
  {
    "back": "incomodar (trouble or annoy (someone) with frequent or persistent requests or interruptions)",
    "front": "pester (if you don’t know I’ll pester Marcelo)",
    "created_at": "24/10/2024, 15:33:59",
    "id": 1729780439823
  },
  {
    "back": "esforçar ao máximo (eu decidi me esforçar ao máximo para melhorar minha fluencia em ingles nesse fim de ano)",
    "front": "all out (I decided to go all out to improve my English fluency this end of the year)",
    "created_at": "15/11/2024, 14:45:21",
    "id": 1731681921171
  },
  {
    "front": "jumble (the questions are jumbled up) [noun / verb]",
    "back": "uma mistura de confusa de coisas [noun] / misturar coisas de maneira bagunçada [verb]",
    "created_at": "06/01/2025, 11:43:28",
    "id": 1736174608455
  },
  {
    "front": "ahorrar (ahorre dinero con tales concelos)",
    "back": "popuar (poupe dinheiro com tais conselhos)",
    "created_at": "15/01/2025, 13:04:27",
    "id": 1736946267861
  },
  {
    "front": "fussy (it's ok with the cool & calm clients but with the fussy ones..)",
    "back": "temperamental / dificil de agradar",
    "created_at": "03/02/2025, 15:26:28",
    "id": 1738596388715
  },
  {
    "back": "chover bastante (está chovendo bastante aqui no momento)",
    "front": "piss down (it's really pissing down here at the moment)",
    "created_at": "10/02/2025, 11:11:09",
    "id": 1739185869629
  },
  {
    "front": "nitpick (you're always nitpicking - it's so annoying!) [verb / noun]",
    "back": "ser picuinha, encontrar falhas que não são importantes [verb] / picuinha, pequeno detalhe [noun]",
    "created_at": "24/02/2025, 16:09:04",
    "id": 1740413344750
  },
  {
    "back": "se ao menos (se ao menos meu filhos me obedecessem / se ao menos meu marido me amasse mais)",
    "front": "if only + verb (if only my children would obey me / if only my husband were more loving)",
    "created_at": "02/04/2025, 14:35:46",
    "id": 1743600946778
  },
  {
    "front": "short handed (sorry asking this, I know you are short handed)",
    "back": "com falta de pessoal (desculpa pedir isso, eu sei que voce está com falta de pessoal)",
    "created_at": "28/04/2025, 11:18:33",
    "id": 1745835513794
  },
  {
    "back": "guarda-sol, de praia, de carro etc (o guarda-sol ajuda a reduzir a temperatura interior)",
    "front": "sunshade (the sunshade helps reduce the interior temperature)",
    "created_at": "28/04/2025, 11:20:48",
    "id": 1745835648903
  },
  {
    "front": "invaluable (Meric was invaluable to the company)",
    "back": "inestimável, indispensável, extremamente util",
    "created_at": "13/05/2025, 10:39:04",
    "id": 1747129144189
  },
  {
    "front": "chase up (I’m just chasing up with the team at The Loop today on the next steps)",
    "back": "acompanhar, cobrar, relembrar (gentilmente)",
    "created_at": "14/05/2025, 11:39:18",
    "id": 1747219158328
  }
]